Let's write a custom exception for our GitHub API.
I'm going to make a new class here, our new Python file here,
and I'm going to call it exceptions.py.
As you organize your Python code,
you'll see that this is kind of a common practice of putting a lot of your custom exceptions in an exceptions module.
So I'm going to call it GitHub API.
Usually ending these custom subclasses in error or exception is the norm,
so that you know exactly how to use it.
What do I use as the base class?
Exception.
And I'm going to have a constructor here,
and going back to our final exercise.
Looking here, we're raising runtime error.
It's not great, right?
It's when you know those built-in exception classes,
we're not really doing the right thing,
because all sorts of different other scenarios might cause a runtime error.
So something we might want to pass in here
as the status code that we got back from the API.
Specifically for those in class,
because this API has a rate limit,
we want to check for four or three to see if that rate limit was reached.
And so I'm going to take a status code here.
And then I'm going to say if my status code is equal to four or three,
I'm going to say my message was rate limit reached.
Otherwise,
any other type of status code,
I'm just going to say the status code was status code.
You have three assets on the message there.
Oh, thank you.
Okay.
So I'm still missing one thing.
What do I have to do to make sure that my message gets passed up to exception?
All super.
And pass in our new custom message.
And I'm going to run this file from.
With interactive mode, just so I can show you.
Very quickly, intermediate Python called the spiral exception stop UI.
Okay, so I have my GitHub API or.
And remember, we don't just make a new instance of it.
If we want to see the exception get raised, we use the raise keyboard keyword.
And if I try not to pass any arguments, we'll see.
Type error that is missing one required position or argument, the status code, right?
So let's say the status code is 500.
It will say, you know, get hub API or really helps me narrow it down.
The status code was 500.
What if I pass in a 403 here?
Great, let me reach.
So now we can be a lot more specific and useful.